all right this video is about using vs
code Visual Studio code how to install
it and specifically how to set it up to
do Local web
development all right that is it local
documentation web development or
whatever you want right that's all it is
we're not going to get into all the side
quests that you can do with this that is
the primary goal here so we're going to
we're going to go get vs code
so the first thing we're going to do is
go to visual studio space code do not
forget code people uh this is the one
you
want uh at least one person is going to
say why aren't you using codium because
I don't care about codium just use V
Studio code it's fine don't let anybody
tell you differently if you care then
you can use that instead but right now
just use V Studio code you'll be good to
go you download for Windows download for
Mac download for whatever it's using a
technology called electron which allows
it to be used everywhere um there's
another video about editors and whe why
your editor might suck and which one you
should use that justifies the pick
selection of this editor as your first
editor um I'm not going to show you how
to download and click on the install
thing and then accept all those things
that's you can know how to do that
that's that's pretty basic um codium is
supposed to be privacy uh oriented and
de debloated the problem is is it
doesn't get updated as quickly as this
does so that's an issue same with chrome
it's the reason I use Chrome instead of
chromium chromium has been I don't want
to talk about it that's a separate video
um so this is the one we're installing
um and once you have that installed then
you can run it now I we've talked about
this in another video but the way I run
everything is using what I call search
Centric uh commands which means that I
tap in this case the Windows key and I
type uh Visual Studio code which then
pops up and I hit enter it's much faster
to do that than to go to my mouse and
click around and find the thing that I'm
going to run so this is Visual Studio
code uncustomized Visual Studio code you
can tell that there's nothing here you
can read all the stuff that you want to
this changes every time so um but the
method of installing the method you
started up has not changed um but the
the main piece of this for web
development that I want to show you I'm
going to go ahead and close the welcome
thing you can become familiar with this
on your own H you're an DCT you don't
need me to tell you everything right you
you should be experimenting with this
and coming up with your own things and
everything so I encourage you to do that
I'm not going to do all that
experimentation with you right now
there's only one key requirement that I
want to show you for web development and
that is in the extensions box right here
um if you search it actually might come
up as one of the most popular ones it's
right here it's called live server okay
um and some of these other extensions
you might want to use depending on
different purposes we are not going to
be doing python or or Jupiter or
Jupiter's for machine learning python
jupyter notebook kind of people we're
not going to be using any of these other
things now you might choose to use them
but again this is for web development
and I personally believe live server is
required for this um there is another
technology that I also like called
browser sync um but in order to use that
you need to know how to use the terminal
and at this point we're not assuming you
know the terminal I'm assuming the only
thing you know is vs code you don't know
the terminal yet now when you do know
the terminal I may discuss with you uh
another technology called browser sync
um which allows you to preview your web
apps and web uh documents on multiple
devices at the same time and I actually
have a video of me uh with a phone an
iPad and a computer all at the same time
simultaneously previewing the
development as I'm doing it which is
phenomenally amazing if you're doing
graphic web applications development or
you're doing Progressive apps and that
kind of thing so watch for that video
that's called browser sync but for our
purposes today we just want some way to
preview our stuff that is being served
from a web server okay let me one last
little piece on this why why not just
open up the file from the web browser
think about that for a second the reason
it can't you can't do that is because
there are certain technologies that do
not work unless they are served from a
web browser a web server sorry a web
server up to a web browser they have to
be served and that's why we want a
server one of those technologies that I
used to use in private school uh game
development camps is phaser phaser JS
will not work for security reasons
unless it is served from a server you
cannot import or use JavaScript files in
your your your games and stuff like that
unless they're coming from a server so
that's why we want a server we're going
to go ahead and install it
um uh trust workspace and
install um I'm going to go ahead and do
that make sure you understand the
implications for yourself before you do
what I'm doing here um so once this is
on it says new live server at five b
activation load time improve show
details I don't know what that's about I
really don't care uh if you wanted to
disable it you could um but now that
it's installed we can do some pretty
cool things um so for example um you see
whoops where is it where is the launch
disable un I think it's already on by
default it's been a while since I've use
it so I'll hopefully I'll make the same
mistakes you guys would make um let's
actually try it so let's try to we don't
have a folder yet um let's open a new
folder on the desktop I don't care we'll
call it um wait this is desktop so
select folder how about new folder I
know I'm on window Windows if you're on
Mac it's fine uh if you're on Linux
already then you know what you're doing
so uh let's say I don't know
game uh no we're not going to do game
because that's gonna make me okay fine
we'll do game game so we're g to click
on game go in here uh select folder so
this then becomes your project right uh
trust authors of the files in the parent
D parent folder of desktop yes I do this
is new they didn't have that before uh
get started with vs code we don't need
any of that and close that so let's make
a new
file uh and let's name the file
index.html which we'll cover that in a
different video but I this is just how
you get started um and actually this is
HTML it's actually not
HTML and now you see that right there
that means it hasn't been saved yet uh
the first thing you might want to do is
set up autosave turn this on um when
autosave is on anytime you make any
changes they'll be saved
uh this is some text how about that and
let's see if I can re see I want to see
if I can remember how a preview um which
has been a while since I've done this
where is it I oh there it is down there
so is it covered up it is covered up so
down in the bottom corner corner is go
live and you can click on go live and
it's like do you want oh my lord it's
I'm so sorry I I apologize for the
flashbang um
that I apologize for the flashbang but
as you can see it's changed it um this
is some uh
seriously uh bright uh text all right
and then you see how it Autos saved and
ALT Tab and you can get you can go see a
refresh and it'll do it now the downside
of this which is not as good as browser
sync when you use browser sync it
automatically changes it you don't have
to do a re refresh so there you go you
can just do the refresh there um and
that is it my friends that is all there
is to this um you just want to have live
server on and you I'm so sorry for the
flashbangs on that video but um but that
that's how you do that that's how you do
that and the rest of this is going to be
about how to do editing videos and stuff
like that hello so that's the end of
that video